Welcome to part two of First Time Homebuyer Series.
In this episode, we're gonna be going over negotiations.
So here we are, you found the house you like,
and now it's go time.
It's time for your realtor to sit down with you,
do a comparable market analysis,
and show you similar properties that closed
so you don't overpay.
So after your realtor does the comparable market analysis
for you, you should have the market value
of the property.
I recommend offering anywhere between five and 7%
below the market value, not the list price,
below the market value of the property.
Anything below five to 7% of the market value
is considered disrespectful
and you might turn off the seller to offer completely.
List price is what the seller thinks this property is worth,
market value is what it's actually worth.
There's one more opportunity you have to renegotiate
and that's when the appraisal comes in.
If it's lower than what you offer,
you might be able to bring the seller down a little.
If you'd like a free homebuyer guide,
or you see a homeownership on the Verizon's for you
in the next six months to two years,
DM me directly or call me at 917-951-2142.
My name is Shurif and I work with Homes and Rest Realty
in Staten Island, New York.